Just now joining us, Julius?
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
今頃 遅れて合流なんて―
Thanks for gracing us with your presence.
ユリウスったら いいご身分だよね
Please... You will tarnish my reputation.
（ユリウス･ユークリウス）
それを言われては 面目も立たない
But I am not the man called "Julius."
だが 私はユリウスという
人物ではない
Let's see...
そうだな ユーリと
名乗っておこうか
Perhaps I shall go by "Juli."
Even if it is temporary,
仮にではあるが―
騎士の身分を持つ
人物が―
a man with a knight's status must never lower himself to the rank of mercenary.
傭(よう)兵に
身を落とすことなど―
あってはならない
The man you see here is not
Julius Juukulius, the knight,
ここにいるのは―
ユリウス･ユークリウスという
騎士などではなく―
but a simple wanderer called Juli.
ユーリという ただの流れ者だ
A proper household's code
of chivalry is a real pain, huh?
ちゃんとした家の騎士道は
面倒っちいよね
What a joke.
（ナツキ･スバル）くっだらねえ
It seems you're doing better than I expected.
思ったより元気そうで なによりだ
体の調子はどうだろうか
How are you holding up?
Well, there were only some scratches!
まあ
かすり傷だったし―
A little spit fixed them right up!
ツバつけときゃ治った
みたいな
What about you?
そっちのほうこそ―
Been busy writing apologies
for going all-out on an amateur?
素人相手に マジに
なっちゃったせいで―
始末書と反省文書くのが
忙しくなかった？
I wasn't referring to that.
その話ではなく―
I was talking about your scars of victory from the witchfiend subjugation.
魔獣討伐の 名誉の
負傷の話をしたかったんだが
But I'm glad your wounds from before seem to have healed.
その節の傷も復調したようで
なによりだ
Thanks to our combined efforts,
we managed to take down the White Whale.
みんなのおかげで
白鯨を倒すことができた
But it's not over yet.
けど まだ終わりじゃない
上等かましてくれた 魔女教に
おとし前をつけさせなきゃならねえ
I have a score to settle with those Witch Cult
bastards that picked a fight with me.
Once that's done, the White Whale's subjugation will be complete.
そこまでして やっと
白鯨の討伐完了だ
The Witch Cult is next!?
（ミミ･パールバトン）
次は魔女教？
Can we trust allegations that the White Whale and the Witch Cult are connected?
（ティビー･パールバトン）
白鯨と魔女教が
関係ありという情報は―
信頼できるですか？
We only came to serve as reinforcements for the White Whale's subjugation—
僕たちは あくまで
白鯨討伐の援軍に…
ポキュン！
What was that for?
何するですか！
If you can't believe him,
このお兄さんが
信じらんないなら―
then you just need to believe me!
ティビーは お姉ちゃんのこと
信じてついてくればいいの！
I'd prefer it if you believed me, though.
できれば 俺のことも
信じてほしいところだ
I don't like to think about it,
思い出したくもねえが―
but I've run up against the Witch Cult before.
魔女教と出くわしたことがあってな
I learned it then.
そん時 聞いたんだ
Didn't you look into that, Old Man Wil?
ヴィル爺(じい)も その辺
調べてたよね？
I would not term it definitive evidence,
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
確証と言える程ではありませんが
but the distributions of Whale
appearances and Cult activities
白鯨の出現分布と魔女教の活動に
符合する点が多く見られました
coincided in several respects.
That makes it doubly credible!
なら 信ぴょう性も倍増だ
On that note,
つーわけで―
we're going to head for the Mathers domain.
これから俺たちが向かうのは
メイザース領
The Witch Cult is hiding in the forest there.
そこの森に 魔女教が潜んでる
奴らを倒す方法は
至ってシンプル
The way we defeat them is as simple as it gets.
Raid them before they can read our movements,
こっちの動きが割れる前に
カチコミ たたきつぶす
and crush them!
Is there a way to protect the villagers?
（コンウッド･メラハウ）
村人の 安全確保は…
I asked Anastasia-san and Russell-san
（スバル）
アナスタシアさんと
ラッセルさんに頼んで―
to talk to the merchants along the highway.
街道近くにいる行商人に
声かけてもらった
Under the condition that Margrave Mathers buys their cargo at asking prices,
メイザース辺境伯が 積み荷は
言い値で買い取るって条件で
they'll ask the merchants to evacuate
the Arlam villagers and Roswaal mansion residents.
ロズワール邸と
アーラム村の人たち―
まとめて避難させて
くれねえかってな
And a messenger from Crusch-san's household
あとは 一足先に
クルシュさんの所の使者が―
is headed for the mansion
with a handwritten letter.
親書を持って 屋敷に向かってる
There will be chaos if we don't notify Emilia and the rest about the alliance and such.
同盟関係の話とか―
エミリアたちに知らせておかないと
混乱するからな
Sounds like we're all ready.
（リカード･ウェルキン）
準備万端ってとこやな
Yeah!
We have never enjoyed such an advantage in a battle with the Witch Cult.
魔女教に対して―
これほど優位に挑める戦いは
なかったでしょう
Yeah.
ああ ユリウスたちも
合流したおかげで―
With Julius and his crew, we don't have to worry about being outnumbered.
人数的な不安は消えた
I would like to offer one correction.
（ユリウス）
１つだけ 訂正したいのだが―
My name is Juli.
私の名前はユーリだよ
そこは 気をつけてもらいたい
Please take care to use it.
Save the role-playing for situations where it actually matters!
その設定 公的な場面以外じゃ
ジャマなだけだろ！
あれだけ 死ぬかと思うぐらい
しんどい白鯨戦があった
The battle with the White Whale was so tough, I thought I'd die.
Some of us did die.
実際 死んだ人もいるし―
Others vanished, never to return.
消えたまま
帰ってこない人たちもいる
ここにいる誰も死なないで
完勝しよう
Let's get ourselves a decisive victory without losing anyone here.
Let's all return home alive!
みんなで 生きて帰ってこようぜ
So, you really pulled out a win?
（ユリウス）
本当に やってのけたのだね
Huh?
The subjugation of the White Whale
こたびの白鯨討伐―
was a long-standing desire of the Imperial Knights.
本来であれば 王国騎士団が
果たさねばならない 宿願だった
It seems I owe you my thanks.
礼を 言わねばなるまいね
You don't have to force it.
別に 無理して言うことねえよ
For putting an end to a calamity that all nations ignored for far too long,
各国が 長年にわたって
放置してきた災厄に―
終止符を打ったことに―
I thank you.
感謝を
I'm...
（スバル）
俺も… ありがてえって思ってる
援軍寄こしてくれて
grateful to you too.
For coming to back us up.
あんなことがあったのによ
Even after what happened.
About that, I was...
あん時のことは 俺が…
Oh, damn it! Crap!
ああ クソー！ チクショウ！
I know, okay!? I know all too well now!
分かってるよ んなこと
今なら分かるさ！
It was my fault.
俺が悪かった ごめん
あ… 謝ります
Sorry. I... I apologize.
I apologize as well.
こちらこそ 非礼をわびよう
I cannot take back my words and actions,
あの時の言葉と 行い―
その全てを
撤回することはないが―
but I apologize, from the bottom of my heart, for belittling you.
それでも 君を
侮ったことだけは 心から
（スバル）悪かった けど―
I'm sorry, but...
I hate your guts.
俺は お前が大嫌いだ
I feel bad for what happened, and I'm grateful you're here.
悪いと思ってるし―
今 来てくれたことには
感謝もしてる
But I still hate your guts.
けど 俺はお前が大嫌いだ
Seriously, I hate you from the deepest, darkest depths of my heart!
本当に 心の底から
ものすごい 嫌いだ！ フン
それでいい
That is fine.
I have no intention of befriending you, either.
私も 君と友人になれるような気は
なかなかしないのだから
（スバル）
さあ 毎度のことだが
勝負しようぜ
All right, as I say every time,
let's get this fight started.
Bring it on, Fate!
運命様 上等だ
You must be exhausted, Lia.
（パック）
疲れたでしょ リア
少し眠ったほうがいいよ
You should rest a bit.
No.
I don't think I'll be able to fall asleep.
私はなんだか 寝つけそうにない
What about you? Aren't you tired?
パックこそ 疲れたでしょ？
I'm fine.
僕は平気　森の結界も
全部張り直したし―
The forest barrier is all fixed up too.
You don't have to worry about anything!
何も心配いらないよ
Yeah.
But...
でも…
This feels like the time
（スバル）
静かな部屋の隅っこに―
I found a cockroach in the corner of a quiet room.
ふと ゴキブリを
見つけた時の感覚だ
You were drawn to the smell, huh?
においにつられて出てきたな
ホウ酸団子 真っ青
Perfect cockroach bait...
Do I really smell that bad?
やっぱ 俺って―
そんなににおう？
Thanks for coming to meet me.
お出迎え ご苦労さん
Sorry to drop this on you
when you just got here,
出てきてくれたとこ悪いが―
詳しい話は お前らの頭に聞くよ
だから ジャマするな
but I'll talk things out with your boss.
So don't get in my way.
If they'd stuck around long enough
for me to order them
いっそ 荷物まとめて
田舎に帰れ―
to gather their stuff and go home, this would've been easier.
なんて命令まで
聞いてくれりゃ―
楽なのになあ
I have been waiting for you, believer in love.
（ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ）
お待ちしておりましたデス
寵(ちょう)愛の信徒よ
I am a Sin Archbishop in the Witch Cult.
私は魔女教 大罪司教
“怠惰”担当―
Archbishop of Sloth,
ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ―
Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti, at your service.
デス！
I welcome you, beloved child, blessed with love.
歓迎するのデスよ
寵愛を受けし 愛し子
Wonderful!
すばらしい アハハ
すばらしいー
Wonderful!
よう
Hey.
思わぬ大歓迎に 恐縮だよ
I really appreciate the unexpected welcome.
But I'm not sure I really feel this "love" you keep bringing up.
いまいち その寵愛ってのの
実感に欠けるとこなんだが
It always begins suddenly.
始まりは突然なのデス
Everyone, on a certain day,
誰しも ある日を境に
自分が愛されていることに気づく
realizes that they are loved.
They feel the love!
愛に 愛に愛に愛に
愛に愛に愛に愛にー
The love! The love! The love! The love! The love! The love! The love!
Um, and what am I supposed to do now?
（スバル）
えーと それで？
俺はこれからどうすればいい
Ah, the rich scent of the witch's love...
ああー この芳じゅんな魔女の愛
You wouldn't happen to be Pride, would you?
もしや あなた“傲慢”では
ありませんデスか？
Of the six Sin Archbishops,
大罪司教の ６つの席の内―
only Pride's seat remains vacant.
“傲慢”のみが
未だに空席なのデスよ
You have
あなた―
received the Gospel, haven't you?
福音は 受け取っているはず
デスね？
The Gospel?
福音？
My brain
（ペテルギウス）脳が―
trembles!
震！ える！
Presentation of the Gospel, proof of love...
福音の提示を
寵愛の証を 証証―
Proof! Proof! Proof! Proof!
証 証 ヒヒヒヒヒー
Huh?
My Gospel has no account of you.
私の福音書に
あなたの記述はないのデス
That book is the Gospel?
（スバル）あの本が福音？
Then why did you appear here?
ならば あなたは―
一体 なぜにこの場所に
現れ 訪れ―
Why visit here?
What fortune are you here to deliver!?
どういった幸いを
私にもたらすの―
デス！ か！
Oh! So that's the Gospel!
ああー それが福音ね
なるほど なるほど
I see, I see...
I understand, I understand.
分かりました 分かりました
You should have just said so.
それならそうと
言ってくれないとー
Aw, darn it! I'm sorry!
ああっと マズった
悪(わり)い悪い
What?
何です？
My Gospel is, well, you know...
（スバル）
俺の福音だけど アレだ―
I used it as a coaster, and it got messy.
鍋敷きに使って 汚れたから―
So I threw it out.
ばっちくて捨てた
Proof of love!
寵愛の証 怠惰なる権能
見えざる手ー！
Authority of Sloth: Unseen Hand!
何です！
What?
It's just an "unseen hand," right?
見えざる手なんだろ？
So if I can see it, I can evade it!
見えてりゃ よけられないほどじゃ
ないってこった！
You can see my Unseen Hand!?
あなた 今 私の見えざる手を！
Okay, I'm just about done buying time!
時間稼ぎは そろそろおしまいだ！
生き埋め上等だ！
Prepare to be buried alive!
Suffer, as you regret the things you've done!
てめえらのやってきたこと
苦しんで悔やめ！
How... How could this be?
（ペテルギウス）
何たる… 何たることデスか
My fingers, so cruelly, so mercilessly,
私の指先を
こうも無残に 無慈悲に―
so chaotically, so arbitrarily,
so artlessly, so meaninglessly...
無秩序に 無作為に
無造作に 無意味に
My brain... My brain trembles!
脳が！ 脳が震えるー！
Yikes, that guy's kinda scary.
ウヘー！ なんかおっかないな
あの おっさん
I think all the Witch Cult members are like that.
魔女教徒なんて みんな
あんなものだと思うですよ
Yes, of course...
（ペテルギウス）
ああー そうデスね
Fine... Fine.
いいデス いいデス
I understand. Let's do this.
I'm ready to do this.
分かったのデス やりましょう
やるとするのデス
The time has come to learn which of us is worthy of her love!
私とあなたと―
どちらが寵愛にふさわしいか
競い合う時なのデス！
Her love! Yes, her love!
愛に そう 愛にー！
Sorry to interrupt your fun, but...
（スバル）
盛り上がってるとこ
悪いんだけどな
—ove?
I have someone else lined up to take you on!
（スバル）
お前の相手は
別の人に任せてある！
（ヴィルヘルム）てやーっ！
（スバル）
お… 終わった… よな
I-It's over... Right?
He's very much dead!
完全に死んでまーす
The capital's most powerful healer guarantees it.
王都最高の治癒術師が
太鼓判 押したげる
I see...
そう… か
Wilhelm-san, I'm sorry I asked
something so unreasonable of you.
ヴィルヘルムさん
無理言ってすみませんでした
Was it unreasonable?
“無理”ですかな？
Isn't cutting someone down
without warning, from behind,
不意打ちで 背後から
切りかかるとか―
the worst thing a knight can do?
騎士として 最悪でしょ
Chivalry is becoming a thing of the past.
すでに 廃れつつある騎士道ですよ
You need not concern yourself with that.
気になさることではありません
Hmm... Doesn't look like
he's carrying anything useful.
（ティビー）
んー たいした物は
持ち歩いてないみたいですです
You sure are ransacking his corpse like it's the obvious thing to do, shorty.
当たり前のように 死体の懐
まさぐるんだな おチビちゃん
I'm not shorty. I'm Tivey.
おチビではなく ティビーです
I think it's our right to search out
the spoils of battle.
戦利品をあさるのは
普通に 権利だと思うですよー
What is this?
これは… 何です？
I think it's the book that
Petelgeuse called a "Gospel."
（スバル）
あっ それ たぶんペテルギウスが
福音って呼んでた本だぞ
Eep! This is a Gospel!?
えー！ これが福音ですです？
Oh, no! I touched it!
うわー 触っちゃったです！
I can't read it...
読めねえ
フェリス お前 これ読め…
Ferris, can you read this?
（２人）にゃあ！
Whoa, nyo way! Don't point that thing at me!
ちょっと うかつに
こっち向けにゃい！
And don't do something as stupid as trying to read a Gospel!
スバルきゅんも―
福音に目を通すとか
バカなマネしないで！
Is it that dangerous?
そんなにヤバイ本なのか これ
The Gospel is the proof that one belongs to the Witch Cult.
（ヴィルヘルム）
福音とは 魔女教徒の証
奴らにとっての
教典のようなものです
They're basically their sacred texts.
Sacred texts?
（スバル）教典？
Rumors say one is delivered to anyone with the potential to join the cult.
（フェリックス）
ウワサだと 魔女教に入る
見込みのある人のところに―
送られてくるんだって
And once a person gets it... Imagine that.
で 届いたら最後
あーら不思議―
They're nyow a devout member of the Witch Cult.
敬虔(けいけん)な魔女教徒の
できあがりーってお話にゃの
How shady can you get?
（スバル）
何だよ そのうさん臭い話
Well, I guess I'll take this with me.
まあ 一応回収しとくか
If I can decipher it, maybe I can
figure out what the Witch Cult really is.
解読できれば 魔女教の実態が
分かるかもしんねえしな
（ミミ）ぷへーっ
Hey, hey, we've butchered the enemies here,
ねえねえ こっちの敵は
もうぶっ殺したんだし―
so shouldn't we go make sure the others have butchered their enemies too?
ほかのみんながぶっ殺せたかどうか
確かめに行ったほうがよくない？
You know, as adorable as you look,
見た目の愛らしさに反して―
you say some pretty disturbing things.
ホント お前 しゃべる内容
物騒だよなあ
Aw, I'm adorable? You're makin' me blush!
（ミミ）
フッフフー かわいいとか
照れますな！
Then the subordinates that Petelgeuse called "fingers" number ten, in total?
ペテルギウスが指先と呼ぶ
配下の集団は―
全部で… 10でしたか
I think one of them is pinned under there.
１つは あそこで
下敷きになってるはずです
Ten minus one is nine!
10-１は９
残り ここのーつ！
So nine are left!
では 行きますかな
Then, shall we go?
But he really is dead, right?
けど 本当に死んでるよな
He won't come back
the second we look away, right?
目 離した隙に
復活とかしないよな？
Fine... If you're that worried, we'll make sure.
もー そんなに
心配だったら 念のため
We crushed two fingers here.
（ユリウス）
こちらで 指先は２本潰した
A few of the cultists were skilled, but they posed no real threat.
魔女教徒にも数名は
手だれがいたが 問題ない
いずれも 大過なく退けたよ
Driving them off, we made no error.
I'm glad it went well for you guys too.
そっちも順調でよかった
I'll take that as a sign that
your news is good as well?
（ユリウス）その様子だと―
そちらも吉報を持ち帰ったと
思ってよさそうだ
Yep, we took out Petelgeuse!
ああ ペテルギウスは
討ちとったぜ
And since this guy is such a worrywart,
お兄さん 心配性だから―
we blasted him to bits with one more "kaboom" after we killed him!
ぶっ殺したあとは 最後にもう１度
ドカーンってバラバラにして―
All to bits!
Then, that leaves the simple task
of mopping up the remnants, huh?
したら あとは
残党とっちめるだけの―
簡単なお仕事やな
We'd better hurry and take care of 'em
before my lady turns into an old granny.
早(はよ)う済ませんと―
お嬢が お婆ちゃんになって
しまうから 急がななー
Oh, that was my best joke, y'know!
あっ これ ワイの鉄板の
冗談なんやけど！
We rendezvous soon with
the dragon carriages you arranged.
（ユリウス）
じきに 君の手配した
竜車との合流もある
Let us eliminate the remaining fingers and greet our victory together.
残る指先を殲(せん)滅し 全員で
勝利を迎えようじゃないか
Okay, Subaru-kyun, time for the bait.
じゃあ スバルきゅん
おとりおとり におい出して
Put out that smell!
Breathe in...
はーい 吸ってー
And out...
吐いてー
And out... And out... And out...
（ミミ）
吐いてー 吐いてー 吐いてー
Hey, hang on! Don't be crazy!
（スバル）
ちょっと待て！
ムチャぶりすんな！
So I guess...
なんつーか これが片づくと―
Once this is all done,
we'll go back to being friend and foe.
敵 味方に戻るんだよな
こいつらと
How confident of you to worry
about what is yet to come.
先の心配とは
余裕があるようだね
Well, sorry.
悪かったよ
It's going almost too well,
so I may have lowered my guard.
順調すぎるぐらい順調で
気が抜けてたのかもしれ…
Get down!
しゃがめー！
What is this?
なんや？ 何が起きとんのや！
What's goin' on!?
The Unseen Hand...
（スバル）見えざる手だ！
Petelgeuse should be dead!
ペテルギウスは死んだはずだ
なのに 誰が！
So who's—
おわっ！
（スバル）ああーっ！
（ヴィルヘルム）スバル殿！
Subaru-dono!
Damn it!
（スバル）ああ クッソー！
Ah!
（女狂人）
ああ！ 脳が 震 える
My brain... trembles...
Who are you?
（スバル）何なんだ お前…
Wh-Who the hell are you?
な… 何なんだよ
Are you Petelgeuse's...
お前は ペテルギウスの…
Finger, yes!
指先
デス！
（スバル）うっ 離せ…
Let me go...
I am a finger,
（女狂人）
私は指先　私は寵愛に報いる者
one who reciprocates love.
A faithful, diligent disciple who will carry out
試練を執行し
愛のしるべに従い―
the Ordeal, following the guidance of love!
忠実にして勤勉なる使徒！
A copy?
（スバル）
コピー ペテルギウス本体の複製体
A replica of... the original Petelgeuse?
If so, this couldn't... possibly get any worse.
だとしたら 最悪どころの
話じゃねえぞ
Sniff, sniff.
The love that hangs from you does not compare to that of a mere follower.
あなたの身にまとう寵愛は
一介の信徒の比ではなく―
It is equal to that of a Sin Archbishop.
大罪司教に匹敵するのデス
非常に不満 不服
不本意 不愉快―
It is exceedingly
displeasing, dissatisfying, disagreeable,
discomforting, disproportionate, discordant!
不条理 不合理では
あるのですが―
But that is the proof that you are Pride!
それこそが―
あなたが“傲慢”である証！
あー 何度も言わせんなよ
Don't make me keep saying it...
I'm not even close to Pride.
俺は 傲慢どころか
入会特典の本も もらってねえよ
I've never gotten a free book,
even as a membership perk!
My! Are you being stubborn?
なーんと強情なのデスかー
Still, soon enough, you will quite readily...
ですが そんな あなたも
すーぐに素直に… あっ
The Gospel...
福音… 我が愛の使命！
The guidance of my love!
The Gospel that allows me,
though inexperienced, to return love!
未熟な我が身が 正しく
寵愛に報いるための 福音！
It isn't with me now!
それが今 手元にないのデス！
Was it you?
あなた デスか？
You? You? You? You? You? You? You? You!?
あなた あなた あなた あなた
あなたあなたあなたあなた！
Did you steal it!?
あなたが奪ったのデスかー！
Wha...
精霊！
A spirit?
あー！ 精霊ー いっ いっ…
A spirit!
Spirit! Spirit! Spirit!
いっ いやーっ いっ あっ…
Spirit!
精霊ーっ！
Damn it.
（スバル）クソッ…
Is that all you can do?
（女狂人）
その程度なのデスか？
If so...
だとしたら 失望 落胆 絶念
I'm dismayed. Disappointed. Dejected.
Are you two slothful!?
あなたたち―
怠惰デスかー！
My life is spilling out...
命がこぼれる
My blood is running dry.
血が無くなる
My diligent pulse, my life's support,
私の生を支える
勤勉なる脈動が―
is stopping... disappearing.
止まって… 消えて…
Ah, my brain... trembl—
脳が 震え…
The first Sloth we defeated was a double,
最初に私たちが倒した
怠惰は 替え玉で―
and this was the real one?
こっちが 本物だったってこと？
いや どちらが本物かなんて
次元の話ではないのかもしれない
No,
this may not be a matter of which is real.
You mean that there may be more than one Sin Archbishop of Sloth?
つまり 怠惰の大罪司教は
複数人存在すると
Either that...
あるいは―
指先まで含めた
100人がそろって―
Or all hundred followers, including the fingers, are the Sin Archbishop of Sloth.
怠惰の大罪司教
I dragged you all into this.
（スバル）
俺が 巻き込んだ
If I'd realized it sooner, I could have avoided this.
俺が もっと早く
気づいていれば 防げた
I knew what kind of power it was, so I...
あれが どんな能力なのか
分かってた
俺が…
Subaru-dono.
スバル殿
I am sure that many thoughts are running through your mind right now.
おそらく 今のあなたの頭には―
さまざまな考えが
浮かんでおいででしょう
And I am certain none are half-hearted.
いずれも 生半(なまなか)な感情の
ものではないはず
But while it may be inelegant of me, I must say this.
ただ 不粋の極みながら
言わせて頂きます
Fight!
戦え
Even if you have regrets,
後悔があろうと
悔恨(かいこん)に打たれようと 戦え
even if you have remorse, you must fight.
If you have made the decision
for yourself to fight, to struggle,
戦うのだと あらがうのだと
己に そう定めたのであれば―
全身全霊で戦え
then fight with all you have.
Do not give up for one second, one moment, or one instant.
１秒も 一瞬も 刹那も諦めず―
Cling greedily to the victory
you have within your sight.
見据えた勝利に 貪欲に食らいつけ
If you can still stand, if your fingers still move,
まだ立てるのならば
まだ指が動くのならば―
if all your teeth have not broken.
まだ牙が折れていないのならば―
立て　戦え
Stand and fight.
You must fight.
戦えと
You're telling me to get stronger?
強くなれって 言うんですか
No.
いいえ
I am telling you to be strong.
強くあれと
Ready to go?
行きますか
Yeah, let's go.
ああ 行こう
Lend me your wisdom and strength!
知恵と力 貸してくれ！
We're gonna start evacuating
the mansion and village!
屋敷と村の人間の避難を始める！
一刻も早く！
Don't waste a single second!
Right now,
今なら まだ―
the Witch Cult still hasn't noticed that the plain is wide open.
魔女教は平原がガラ空きに
なってることに 気づいてない
We can get Emilia and the others in carriages, and get them to safety in plain sight.
エミリアたちを竜車に乗せて
街道から堂々と逃がせるはずだ
エミリア様たちを逃がして
後顧の憂いがなくなれば―
With Emilia-sama and the others safe,
that's one less weight on our mind.
So we can focus on subjugating the Witch Cult.
魔女教の討伐にも集中できる
Fighting isn't easy when you
know you have a weak point!
弱点背負って戦うのって
大変だもんね
Talk about hitting close to home...
耳が痛(いて)えよ
But you're exactly right.
けど そういうことだ
While I'm at it, let me say one more thing.
ついでだから もう１つ
言っておくけど
Subaru-kyun, you should really
make up with Julius soon.
スバルきゅん―
早めに ユリウスと
仲直りしたほうがいいよ ホント
Soon? We already reconciled after our fight.
（スバル）
早めも何も やり合ったことは
水に流したよ
You didn't see?
見てたろ
That was just for the time being, right?
とりあえずでしょ
You still subconsciously harbor resentment.
本心と無意識に 反発が残ってる
You can rely on Julius.
ユリウスは 頼りにしていいよ
But I admit he is a bit unapproachable
and incomprehensible.
取っつきにくいし
分かりにくいのは認めるけどね
Go on, hurry up.
ほら 早く
Okay, fine!
わーったよ
Uh...
So, hey, there's something
I wanted to say to you...
その だな 改めて―
お前に 言っとかなきゃ
いけないことが…
A  Flashof   Sloth
fu
an
tei
na
shii
so
o
ha
na
re
su
gi
te
ka
ta
ho
u
mi
e
na
i
me
ji
ru
shi
sa
e
na
i
ka
ra
fu
tto
me
wo
to
ji
te
wa
ma
ta
i
no
ru
Oh,
Stay
A
live
i
ma
wa
do
n
na
ko
to
o
mo
tte
ru
no
de
shou
nai
te
i
na
ke
do
hi
to
ri
wa
ya
p
pa
ri
sa
bi
shi
ku
tte
sa
Stay
A
live